20090414 /// http://www.nytimes.com/2009/04/14/science/14angi.html?_r=1&ref=science \  \ On these taxing days, when we become a defiantly bipartisan nation of whiners convinced that we are handing over to the Internal Revenue Service our blood and sweat and mother’s milk, our pound of flesh and firstborn young, maybe it’s time for a little perspective. \ Skip to next paragraph \ RSS Feed \  \     * Get Science News From The New York Times » \  \ Legions before us have donated all these items and more to the public till, and not just metaphorically speaking, either. Benjamin Franklin was right to equate paying taxes with a deeply organic behavior like dying. It turns out that giving up a portion of one’s income for the sake of the tribe is such a ubiquitous feature of the human race that some researchers see it as crucial to our species’ success. Without ritualized taxation, there would be precious little hominid representation. \  \ Moreover, plenty of nonhuman animals practice the tither’s art, too, demanding that individuals remit a portion of their food, labor, comfort or personal fecundity for the privilege of group membership. And just as the I.R.S. depends on threat of audit as much as it does on anybody’s sense of civic responsibility, so do other toll-collecting species ensure compliance by meting out swift punishment against tax cheats. For example, Marc Hauser of Harvard University has found that when a rhesus monkey is out foraging and comes upon a source of especially high-quality food, like, say, a batch of ripe coconuts, the monkey is expected to give a characteristic food call to alert its comrades to the find. “The bad thing about doing a food call is that it means others will come and take some of the food,” said Laurie R. Santos, who studies the primates at Yale University. Yet a monkey who opts to keep mum about its discovery could face worse. Should other group members happen by while the private feast is under way, they will not only claim the food for themselves, but the most dominant among them will also beat the cheater indignantly. \  \ Not everybody is subject to a big macaque attack. Adolescent males that have only recently transferred into the group are not required to issue food alerts. They are, as yet, on probation, and only upon gaining the rights of full citizenship will the young males be expected to shoulder its duties. \  \ The more closely knit an animal society is, and the more interdependent its members, the higher the rate of taxation. Among bell miner birds of Australia, for example, pairs of breeding adults are assisted at the nest by several youthful helpers, usually male. The helpers provision the couple’s fledglings with a steady supply of lerp, sugary casings secreted by plant-sucking insects. And though some scientists had wondered whether lerp wasn’t basically a junk food, offered up to the young bell miners as much for show as for substance, researchers report in the March issue of Animal Behaviour that lerp is, in fact, as important to the fledglings’ growth as is the meatier arthropod prey supplied by their parents. By all evidence, the helper birds are honestly “paying to stay,” trading a valuable currency for the right to remain within the aggressively guarded precincts of a bell miner breeding colony, with the hope of better times and personal propagation opportunities ahead. \  \ Or at least of averting personal injury. Among another Australian species of cooperatively breeding birds, the superb fairy-wren, dominant males notice when their helpers are less than superb about paying their taxes. Should a helper fail to feed and groom the dominant’s nestlings, or to give an alarm call on seeing intruders enter the territory, the dominant male will angrily chase, harass and peck at the helper, for up to 26 hours at a time. In the case of the highly social cichlid fish, fear of punishment inspires delinquent helper fish to ostentatiously redouble their contributions to the communal nest, their digging in the sand, their cleaning and fanning of the eggs — rather like politicians who suddenly pony up three years of back taxes for themselves, the nanny and the gardener. “If they don’t pay their bill, there will be punishment,” said Michael Taborsky of the University of Bern, “so they try to pre-emptively appease the dominant individuals in the group.” \  \ If hope and fear don’t guarantee compliance, there’s always embarrassment. Vampire bats are famous for their willingness to regurgitate a blood meal to feed fellow bats that are down on their luck. In fact, hiding one’s wealth is a problem. A fully fed vampire bat is as bloated as a fraternity water balloon, and the bats appear to rub bellies to see who is in a position to share. “It’s hard to cheat when your stomach is obviously distended,” Dr. Santos said. \  \ It’s also hard to cheat when you live in a small band of big-brained, sharp-eyed individuals, as humans did for vast stretches of our past, which may help explain why we are so easily taxed. “There’s not a human society in the world that doesn’t redistribute food to nonrelatives,” said Samuel Bowles, director of the behavioral sciences program at the Santa Fe Institute. “Whether it’s through the state, or the chief, or a rural collective, or some other mechanism, food sharing of large nutritional packages is quite extensive and has been going on for at least 100,000 years of human history.” In hunting and foraging cultures, the proportional tax rate is so high, said Dr. Bowles, that “even the Swedes would be impressed.” \  \ Take the case of the Ache tribe of Paraguay. Hunters bring their bounty back to a common pot. “The majority of calories are redistributed,” he said. “It ends up being something like a 60 percent income tax.” \  \ Pastoral and herding societies tend to be less egalitarian than foraging cultures, and yet, here, too, taxing is often used to help rectify extreme inequities. When a rich cattle farmer dies among the Tandroy of southern Madagascar, Dr. Bowles said, “The rich person’s stock is killed and eaten by everyone,” often down to the last head of cattle. “That’s a 100 percent inheritance tax.” \  \ Modern taxes are just a “newfangled version of commitment to the group,” said David Sloan Wilson of Binghamton University, the result of the invention of money. Yet even with our elaborate, abstracted tax code, fear of public opprobrium remains an impressive motivator. “It’s expected that powerful, high-status members of society should be contributing more,” Dr. Wilson said. “If they don’t, they won’t remain high status for long.” And for the fat bats among us who just won’t cough up the goods — there’s always jail.
a British toddler gleefully biting the finger /// a British toddler gleefully biting the finger
abate /// to become less strong or decrease, or to make something do this
accrue /// This process allows metadata to be accrued within a file as it passes between operations in a way that has rarely before been achieved.
adamant about /// For an organization that publicizes hidden documents, WikiLeaks is adamant about protecting the anonymity of the document donors.
allure /// It’s hard to avoid the <b>allure</b> of trying to beat the market.
austerity /// A new president can start an era of energy austerity and green power.
awesome /// Many of those who witnessed the first atomic explosion reported that it was \ an (     ) sight. \  \ 1.avuncular  2.endemic  3.awesome  4.erratic \ 
awkward /// http://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/26/technology/no-time-to-text-apps-turn-to-stickers.html?ref=technology \ Stickers also let Japanese users express direct feelings that can be awkward to convey in the formal language, Ms. Morishima said. Refusing an invitation from a colleague for after-work drinks, for example, could cause discomfort in a culture where an outright no is avoided at all costs. But enlist a bear as the messenger and there is less potential for embarrassment on either side, Ms. Morishima said.
beek /// disrespectful or rude behavior, especially toward someone in a position of authority \ 厚かましさ
bristle /// China delivered a bristling response on Monday to the United States’ demand
bustle /// to move around quickly, looking very busy
carry out /// White blood cells (     ) a wide range of highly specialized functions. \  \ 1.play up to  2.drive up  3.bring off  4.carry out \ 
chug along /// Fortunately, the notebook is driven by a power-efficient Intel Core i7 processor. And you have the option of ordering it with either a six-cell (61Wh) or nine-cell (91Wh) battery. With the nine-cell battery, the notebook chugged along for a substantial four hours and 22 minutes when I played a 1080p video file at full screen at 80% brightness. - See more at: http://www.studiodaily.com/2014/06/review-dell-precision-m3800-workstation-2/?hq_e=el&hq_m=2893168&hq_l=17&hq_v=afee45dfbb#sthash.4yUZWw94.dpuf
coerce /// A child may be (     ) into obedience by physical punishment or by the threat \ of it. \  \ 1.extenuated  2.capsized  3.allayed  4.coerced
concussion /// http://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/28/us/politics/talents-on-display-at-white-house-science-fair.html?ref=technology
condone /// Any suggestion that it conducted or condoned the hackers’ intrusions was “groundless and aims to denigrate China.” 
contraband /// A cat has been detained in the grounds of a jail in Brazil with contraband goods for prisoners strapped to its body with tape.
contraception /// The decision temporarily exempts a Christian college from part of the regulations that provide <b>contraception</b> coverage under the Affordable Care Act.
cull /// A site called the Christmas It List culls comments from 50 sites to determine the 25 hottest products.
cumbersome /// http://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/26/technology/no-time-to-text-apps-turn-to-stickers.html?ref=technology \ Line has struck a chord in Japan partly because of the country’s affection for all things cute, experts say. But there are more factors at play. The stiff, written form of the Japanese language can be cumbersome to type on smartphones, and stickers make communication easier and faster, said Ryoko Morishima, who has written several guides on social media.
curb /// Using financial aid to curb suicides
decline /// Google and Yelp declined to comment.
denigrate /// Any suggestion that it conducted or condoned the hackers’ intrusions was “groundless and aims to denigrate China.” 
dissenting voice /// Its own policies seek to shut out dissenting voices.
dour /// making you feel anxious or afraid \ (陰気な)
drowning in debt /// He began drowning in debt to pay his two children's college fees.
elusiveness /// Use the power and elusiveness of the Internet to publish secret documents that someone, somewhere thought should be made public.
enlist /// http://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/26/technology/no-time-to-text-apps-turn-to-stickers.html?ref=technology \ Stickers also let Japanese users express direct feelings that can be awkward to convey in the formal language, Ms. Morishima said. Refusing an invitation from a colleague for after-work drinks, for example, could cause discomfort in a culture where an outright no is avoided at all costs. But enlist a bear as the messenger and there is less potential for embarrassment on either side, Ms. Morishima said.
errand /// A marketing manager, owns a van, but for many errands, he hops on a futuristic-looking contraption.
exert one's influence /// One thing they’ve learned is that a father begins to <b>exert his influence</b> well before birth.
feat /// The new printing presses were considerable feats of engineering.
fledgling /// Line’s characters are not just about better messaging, either. Although Line is free to download, it sells premium-edition stickers, and the characters populate its universe of online games — both big moneymakers for the company. There is the merchandising, as well as a line of peripheral apps, including a weather service, a fledgling e-commerce site and a dedicated camera app that allows users to add characters to their photos.
forgo /// In an effort to save money for a new car, Jason decided to (     ) his annual \ holiday to Hawaii. \  \ 1.enliven  2.forebode  3.forgo  4.enamor \ 
fruition /// These workshops are the fruition of an effort.
fusillade /// Monday’s fusillade by the Chinese not only dismissed Ms. Clinton’s statements, but also depicted the United States as cyberspace’s villain and China as its unwilling victim.
grudge /// Don't worry. He's not the type of person to hold a (     ). He's probably forgotten about it already. \  \ 1.jeer  2.jostle  3.grudge  4.growl
gynecology /// a professor of obstetrics, <b>gynecology</b> and reproductive sciences
hush aside /// to refuse to listen to or consider something (無視する)
impervious /// The lesser-known fortress was totally (     ) to any surprise attack. \  \ 1.revolting  2.impervious  3.irrelevant  4.monolithic \ 
inferior /// The EX1 uses inferior Long-GOP compression.
intemperate /// you don’t have to worry that your <b>intemperate</b> words will come back to haunt you.
jibe with /// It didn’t jibe with the data that has been analyzed.
jostle /// to push or knock against someone, especially in a crowd
jostle for /// http://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/26/technology/no-time-to-text-apps-turn-to-stickers.html?ref=technology
jovial /// The bride's parents were quite (     ) at the fantastic wedding reception. \  \ 1.flagrant  2.vibrant  3.jovial  4.somber \ 
leery of /// But not enough young people are embracing computing — often because they are leery of being branded nerds.
machination /// secret and intelligent plans
make up for /// Big business has to take seriously its responsibility to (     ) the \ ecological damage it has caused. \  \ 1.pay down  2.make up for  3.clear up  4.eke out
marginalize /// he has done it in a way that has marginalized Sunnis and marginalized Kurds.
meddle in /// Trying to dominate the global information flow by meddling in Chinese Internet policies.
nascent /// India had virtually no sales until two years ago, but its nascent market is fast expanding and could eclipse Europe’s in the next year.
obstetrics /// a professor of <b>obstetrics</b>, gynecology and reproductive sciences.
opulent /// The palace's (     ) dining room with its crystal chandeliers was too costly to reconstruct after the fire. \ 1.venal  2.insipid  3.opulent  4.brazen
outright /// http://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/26/technology/no-time-to-text-apps-turn-to-stickers.html?ref=technology \ Stickers also let Japanese users express direct feelings that can be awkward to convey in the formal language, Ms. Morishima said. Refusing an invitation from a colleague for after-work drinks, for example, could cause discomfort in a culture where an outright no is avoided at all costs. But enlist a bear as the messenger and there is less potential for embarrassment on either side, Ms. Morishima said.
permeate /// Tests carried out by the government revealed that toxic waste had (     ) the soil all around the factory. \  \ 1.precluded  2.perpetrated  3.permeated  4.precipitated
profane /// Exposed constantly to violent movies and pornography, the children were brought up in an entirely <font color="#ff0000">profane</font> environment.
pull off /// He pulled off a brilliant first round win.
purport to /// A new app called Xpire (iOS only) <b>purports</b> to let you create self-destructing tweets and Facebook posts.
quixotic /// scientists should be given large budgets, a supercomputer or two and plenty of time to make discoveries and work out the kinks of their quixotic creations. 
reprimand /// When Craig arrived late at work for the third day in a row, his manager gave \ him an official (     ), warning him that habitual lateness was grounds for \ dismissal. \  \ 1.emulation  2.dab  3.elocution  4.reprimand
reproductive science /// a professor of obstetrics, gynecology and <b>reproductive sciences</b>
ruffle /// to offend or upset someone　slightly
skittish /// a person who is ( ) is nervous and afraid to do anyting because of something bad that could happen \ (変わりやすい)
sleigh /// Technology can make shopping go as smoothly as a sleigh over new snow.
smother /// Such a catastrophe finally appeared in the most dramatic form in mid-January, when a thick layer of poisonous pollutants <b>smothered</b> much of northern China and made air in Beijing hazardous to breathe.
steer clear of /// Aiming to steer clear of one of the most contentious debates in the street art world, Google says it will not include images from groups seeking to sell the art or images of it.
subpar /// below an expected level of quality
swindle /// He was accused of a confidence trick that (     ) investors by means of forged \ stock certificates. \  \ 1.garnered  2.inflicted  3.embezzled  4.swindled \ 
take up /// I'm delighted to say that I intend to (     ) your offer and look forward to a \ prosperous business relationship in the future. \  \ 1.come up against  2.take up  3.seal in  4.go bail for
tenuous /// The evidence the defendant produced was too ( ) to prove his innocence. \  \ 1.filthy 2.extravagant 3.tenuous 4.soluble
tinker with /// During the assault, which security analysts said began about 1 a.m. and lasted roughly an hour, hackers tinkered with Twitter’s domain name servers, which are hosted by a Manchester, N.H., company called Dyn.
undermine confidence in /// The court’s action, she added, even “<b>undermines confidence in</b> this institution.” 
upheaval /// secret and intelligent plans
vicariously /// It’s the strongest testament that Google really wants to own this local market, not vicariously but directly.
villain /// Monday’s fusillade by the Chinese not only dismissed Ms. Clinton’s statements, but also depicted the United States as cyberspace’s villain and China as its unwilling victim.
wade into /// With the initiative, Google is the latest organization to wade into debates about how or whether to institutionalize, let alone commercialize, art that is ephemeral and often willfully created subversively.
was supplanted by a brash newcomer /// was supplanted by a brash newcomer
willfully /// With the initiative, Google is the latest organization to wade into debates about how or whether to institutionalize, let alone commercialize, art that is ephemeral and often willfully created subversively.
wilt /// to feel weak, tired, or upset, especially because you are too hot
